{"id":"2017_15","name":"Romans2017_15","memoryVerse":"“I consider that our present sufferings are not worth comparing with the glory that will be revealed in us.” – Romans 8:18 ","dayQuestions":{"one":{"title":"FIRST DAY: Read the notes and the references.","questions":[{"id":"2017_15_1","questionText":"1. What was meaningful to you in the lecture?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_15_2","questionText":"2. What help did you receive from the notes?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"two":{"title":"SECOND DAY: Read Romans 8:28.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:28"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_15_3","questionText":"3. What is the “good” that God works for His people in all things? (See also Romans 8:29-39.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:29-39"}]},{"id":"2017_15_4a","questionText":"4. a. Put Romans 8:28 in your own words. What assurances does this verse offer the believer in every situation?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:28"}]},{"id":"2017_15_4b","questionText":"4. b. How might you pray when struggling with things that you wonder how God will use for good?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_15_5","questionText":"5. What do you learn about God’s attributes and character from Romans 8:28, and how does this challenge or  comfort you?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:28"}]}]},"three":{"title":"THIRD DAY: Read Romans 8:29-30.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:29-30"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_15_6a","questionText":"6. a.  Briefly explain the following concepts. (For help, see John 6:37, 44; Romans 1:6-7; 3:22-26; 8:17-21; Ephesians 1:4-5, 11 or other Bible passages.) Foreknew Predestined Called Justified Glorified","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"John","verse":"6:37"},{"book":"John","verse":"6:44"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"1:6-7"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"3:22-26"},{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:17-21"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"1:4-5"},{"book":"Ephesians","verse":"1:11"}]},{"id":"2017_15_6b","questionText":"6. b. What does Romans 8:29-30 reveal about God, and why is it good news?","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:29-30"}]},{"id":"2017_15_7","questionText":"7.  What are some ways God works to conform believers to the image of His Son? What are some reasons many professing believers do not act like Jesus? (See also Romans 5:3-5; 2 Timothy 3:12, 15-16; Hebrews 5:7-8 or other Bible passages.) ","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"5:3-5"},{"book":"2 Timothy","verse":"3:12"},{"book":"2 Timothy","verse":"3:15-16"},{"book":"Hebrews","verse":"5:7-8"}]},{"id":"2017_15_8","questionText":"8. How do you see God at work in your life to make you more Christlike?","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"four":{"title":"FOURTH DAY: Read Romans 8:31-35.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:31-35"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_15_9","questionText":"9. List the questions and answers in verses 31-35. What conclusions can you draw based on these questions and answers?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_15_10","questionText":"10. With which of the previous questions are you struggling, and how do the answers encourage you? ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"five":{"title":"FIFTH DAY: Read Romans 8:35-39.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:35-39"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_15_11","questionText":"11.  Why does Paul quote Psalm 44:22 to answer the questions verse 35 asks? (See also John 16:33.)","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Psalm","verse":"44:22"},{"book":"John","verse":"16:33"}]},{"id":"2017_15_12a","questionText":"12. a.  How do “all these things” in verses 35-37 relate to “all things” in verses 28 and 32?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_15_12b","questionText":"12. b.  How has a deeper understanding of Christ’s love helped you in a specific difficulty this year?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_15_13","questionText":"13. List things in your life or world events that tempt you to worry or prompt anger and impatience. Use your list to rewrite verses 38-39 as your own statement of confidence in God’s love for you. ","answer":"","quotes":[]}]},"six":{"title":"SIXTH DAY: Review Romans 8:28-39.","readVerse":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:28-39"}],"questions":[{"id":"2017_15_14","questionText":"14. What have you learned about God in this week’s study? How may your group pray for you as you make this truth a part of your life?","answer":"","quotes":[]},{"id":"2017_15_15","questionText":"15. Homiletics for group and administrative leaders: Romans 8:28-39","answer":"","quotes":[{"book":"Romans","verse":"8:28-39"}]}]}}}